PAOLO TAGLIANI

Senior Freelance Software Engineer

PROFILE

Software Engineering consultant with strong theoretical skills and a passion for OpenSource software.

More than ten years of experience building mobile and web applications. Working remotely since 2015.

Customer-oriented and structured method of working, focused on quality and maintainability. Highly motivated to work in a team, both comfortable in big companies as in small teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Linux/FullStack developer

Masterchart - Hybrid Remote

Jan 2021 - Now

Designed and built a complete access management system for banks, composed of several frontend applications and a custom Linux distribution to power personalized in-site kiosk and queue monitor.

Linux/FullStack developer

41 North - Full Remote

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Built a custom Linux distro (based on RaspiOS) to be installed in custom bartop gaming solutions. The system also includes a backend application that stores and distributes legal ROMs. More details at this link.

Mobile and Full Stack Software Engineer

Codermine - Hybrid Remote

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

Built products for third-party clients with mobile and web technologies. Lead a small development team: mentored junior developers, introduced DevOps practices, and improved release cycle and automated testing. Some of the products build include:

- Alarm system configuration app (link)
- Invoice trading platform (frontend and backend) (link)
- Al-based KPI prediction platform (link)

Mobile / FullStack Software Engineer

Ago 2019 - Dec 2019

Palmabit - Hybrid Remote

Full-Stack consultant.

- Circular Economy based delivery service (Link)
- Bluetooth powered chat application (link)

CONTACT

- Via Tormini 74/O, Gavardo (BS), Italy
- ·39 329 2783809
- pablosproject@gmail.com
- pablosproject.com
- 🕤 github.com/pablosproject
- in linkedin.com/in/paolotagliani

EDUCATION

2010 - 2013

Master's Degree in Computer Science University of Brescia

2011 - 2012

Exchange student in Computer ScienceLaSalle Barcelona,
Ramon Llull University

2006 - 2012

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science University of Brescia

LANGUAGES

- Italian (mother tongue)
- · English
- Spanish
- Catalan

Mobile / Full Stack Software Engineer

MobileJazz - Full Remote

Technical and management consultancy for US and European clients. I worked as an iOS developer in the mobile team, then moved to the backend team using Node.JS-based technologies and then worked in web team doing. I was also responsible for DevOps, automation, and custom build solutions in each team I worked in.

Relevant examples of products I worked on:

- IoT custom light control solution (link, blog post)
- Real-time noise monitoring platform (link)
- · Rehab enhancement platform (link)
- TENS remote control application (link)
- Tinder-like social networking application (link)

iOS Developer

May 20<u>13 - Jun 20<u>15</u></u>

TilTap

Worked as an iOS developer in a dedicated team inside a startup incubator. Built several MVPs and products for early stage startups.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Expert: Typescript, Swift, Objective-C/C++ Advanced: C, C++, Javascript, Python

Familiar: Go, Ruby

DevOps: GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD Pipelines, Travis CI

Frameworks: Cocoa, Cocoa Touch, NodeJS, NestJS, ExpressJS, Angular

DB: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Elastic Search, TimeScaleDB

Conainers: Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes

Other skills: Linux administration, AWS services (S3, lambda, IoT, ECS), cloud based server management (Digital Ocean, Linode)

PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- US Patent Hazard Recognition (Patent US11093747B2), link
- Founder of PragmaMark: first iOS/MacOSX Italian developer conference
- · Mentor at CoderDojo Brescia